Christian Alsider

-Data Analyst-

615.330.1896 — christianlalsider@gmail.com — Kingston Springs, TN —linkedin.com/in/christianalsider

-SUMMARY-

Healthcare Data Analyst with over 10 years' experience researching CMS regulations, acquiring, and transforming data into insightful analytics, workflow processes and creating proactive solutions to avoid policy violations. Furnished insights and analytics resulting in an additional 25% in revenue for clinics

-- TECHNICAL SKILLS-

Microsoft Excel —PowerBI —Google Analytics—SQL—Python(Pandas and other libraries) Tableau—Git/Github Trello—Athena—Snowflake—Data Analysis—Slack—Teams—Project Management—Agile Methodology EMR—EHR—SDLC—SCRUM

-PROFESSIONAL HISTORY-

Data Analyst Apprentice — **Nashville Software School**— Nashville, TN — 2022-Present

- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's panda's library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium

Data Analyst Revenue Cycle—Community Health Systems— Nashville, TN — 2015-Present

- Conduct statistical analysis identifying trends in underpayment/overpayments, denials
- Research on CMS policies and regulations
- Create and automate SQL reports in snowflake database containing 300 tables and millions of records
- Collaborate with outside teams to streamline processes resulting in an increase of 200K for one clinic

Lead Accounts Receivable Analyst — Community Health Systems — Nashville, TN — 2013-2015

- Monitor and perform trend analysis for the clinics and research report on anomalies
- Develop accurate and comprehensive test claims for developers, UAT and QA
- Audit clinic fee schedules company wide, resulting in 20% increase in clean claims on first submission
- Mentored new Accounts Receivable Analyst

Provider/Client Information Systems Analyst — Coventry Health—Franklin, TN — 2003-2013

- Act as subject matter expert to key stakeholders
- Create requirements for client request, including data mapping, and reconciliation
- Coordinated weekly, monthly, and quarterly revenue cycle updates meetings
- Influenced process improvements of large-scale reprocessing of claims

-EDUCATION-

Data Analytics— Nashville Software School— Nashville, TN — 2022